本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译   米小勒    Lottie筱妤    kiko     蔡茸茸  我叫魏碧慧
翻译   CS小明漫画家   迷失_绽放  天启章鱼X   小酸奶
时间轴   太太乐叽叽   浓子     后期   小新暴饮暴食
校对   米小勒      总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
.
第一季 第四集
《僵尸国度》前情提要
Previously on Z Nation.
这些都是僵尸咬的
Those are zombie bites.
八个僵尸
Eight of them.
如果我们能把他送到加利福尼亚的实验室
If we can get him to the lab in California,
他们就能用他的血造出更多抗体
they can use his blood and make more of the vaccine.
快射他
Shoot him!
你就是那位救我一命的神枪手  是不是
You're that sharp shooter that saved my ass, aren't you?
孩子  你叫什么
So what's your name, kid?
一万
Ten Thousand.
有什么深意吗
Does it mean anything?
是我要消灭的僵尸的数量
How many zombies I'm going to kill.
第1059个
One thousand fifty-nine.
第1060个
One thousand sixty!
射得好  孩子
Nice shot, kid!
宾夕法尼亚  阿米什乡村
阿米什僵尸
Amish zombies.
搞笑呢
Really?
他们试着把自己与社会的其他部分
They tried to quarantine themselves
隔绝开来
from the rest of society.
避免僵尸将病毒传播到这里来
Keep the Zs from spreading the infection.
罗梅罗[美国地名]沦陷前  阿米什人也就这做派吧
That was before we knew Romero had it right.
我们都携带着病毒
We were all carrying the virus.
无所谓你是什么人  最后会怎么死去
Didn't matter who you were or how you died.
《活死人之夜》  出色的电影  糟烂的现实
Night of the Living Dead. Great movie, sucky reality.
知道我有哪点搞不懂吗  如果不是僵尸传播的病毒
You know what I don't get, If the Zs didn't spread the virus,
那么我们都是如何被感染到的
how did we all get infected?
我听说的最靠谱说法  是由鸟类传播的
Best guess I heard, it was spread by birds.
禽流感病毒中携带着某种寄生虫
Some kind of parasite piggybacked on the bird flu.
在你死之前一直蛰伏在体内
Stays dormant 'till you die.
你要知道
You know
要了解实情就要去找有一手资讯的人
take it from somebody who knows first hand.
僵尸爱吃大脑这种旧闻早已是明日黄花
Other than the fact that they find brains delicious,
一说到僵尸  人人都能变成砖家
when it comes to zombies nobody knows nothin'.
轮到我去了
My turn.
咱俩不熟是吧
Have we just met?
谢了
Thank you.
你快去快回
Hey, hurry up.
我希望在天黑前到达疾控中心
I want to get past DC before dark.
好了好了好了
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我告诉你吧  僵尸只剩个躯壳而已
I'm tellin' ya, there ain't nothin' there.
没有了思维  没有了记忆
No thoughts, no memories.
没有了灵魂
No soul.
啥都没有
Nothin'.
但是它们还是活着的
Well they're not dead.
它们还想要点什么
They want something.
是啊  大脑嘛
Yeah. Brains.
如果你没有意识  没有灵魂
You can't want something if you're not conscious,
是不会想去要些什么的
if you don't have a soul.
当我爸当初受伤后
When my pa was wounded,
他让我在他变异前把他绑紧
he told me to tie him up before he turned.
让我向他保证在他死的时候要施以仁慈
Made me promise to show him mercy when he died.
将大脑杀死  你懂得
Kill the brain, you know?
我下不去手
I couldn't do it.
我不能伤害我的父亲
I couldn't hurt my pa,
无论他变成什么
no matter what he'd become.
我有史以来第一次那么长时间地注视着他
I stared into his eyes for the longest time, just
希望能从他的眼神里看到转机
looking for some sign he was still in there.
那你看到了吗
Did you see anything?
你当时怎么做的
What did you do?
我杀了它
I killed it.
我靠  孩子啊
Damn, kid.
你当时被迫杀了自己老爸吗
You had to put down your own dad?
我没有杀"他"
Didn't kill him.
我杀的是"它"
Killed it.
但如果它当时已经变异  你是如何杀的它
But if it's not alive, how did you kill it?
我刺穿了它
Piked it.
就在这  我杀的第一个
Right here. My first kill.
我一直希望他能知道
I always wish he knew, you know,
不管怎样  知道我当初信守了诺言
somehow knew that I kept my promise.
有人来了  在你们背后
Humans! Six o'clock!
我看着他们呢
I see them.
你的食人族朋友还没死绝吗
Is that more of your cannibal friends?
不  这是另一伙人
No. Something else.
前方有状况
Up ahead!
他要去哪呢
Where's he going?
嘿  孩子
Hey! Kid!
你怎么看
What do you think?
直接撞过去吗
Plow right through?
不  我不想再把车毁了
No, I don't want to wreck the truck again.
我们把它们赶走再赶路吧
Let's pike them and be on our way.
搞什么  我们是在开圣母派对吗
Oh what, are we having a little mercy party?
我们悄悄地过去
Hey, let's do this quietly.
边上说不定还有更多僵尸
There might be more of them nearby.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
她说得对  看看它们的脚
Yeah, she's right. Look at their feet.
别动
Hold it right there!
好了好了  现在放下武器
All right, now drop your weapons
不然送你们上西天
or die
一枪崩了你们
right where you stand.
要么放下武器
Put down the weapons
要么就去吃大脑吧
or eat brains.
天哪  我爱死那孩子了
God, I love that kid.
我们只想要那辆车
Now, we just want the vehicle.
好吗
All right?
只要把卡车给我们
So give us the truck
我们就放你们一条活路  大家秋后算账
and we'll let you live to die another day.
把卡车给他们吧
Give them the truck!
什么都别给他们
Don't give them a goddamn thing!
好好算算吧  加内特
Do the math Garnett.
我们还有别的要紧事
We have other priorities.
把卡车给他们
Get them the damn truck.
听听你朋友说的话
Listen to your friend there.
谁都不想死在这
Nobody wants to die.
不过那辆卡车我们要定了
But we're taking that truck.
一切听你的  加内特
Say the word, Garnett.
给他们...
Let them have it.
卡车
The truck.
把卡车给他们
Let them have the truck.
明智的决定
Smart move.
大家伙儿  我们走
All right guys, let's go!
别管那辆破车了
And leave the junker!
他们走不了多远
They're not gonna get very far.
摩菲
Murphy.
太棒了
Beautiful.
北极光
雷蒙德·瓦尔迪兹中士
Sergeant Raymond Valdez.
来自三角洲部队  确认死亡
Delta Force. Deceased.
马克·哈蒙德中尉
Lieutenant Mark Hammond.
来自三角洲部队  确认死亡
Delta Force. Deceased.
死因
Cause of death.
未知
Unknown.
艾尔文·伯纳德·摩菲
Alvin Bernard Murphy.
零号病患
AKA Patient Zero.
之前在联邦监狱中因邮政诈骗
Previously serving three years in federal prison
服刑过三年
for postal fraud.
义务志愿者  咬痕项目
Compulsory volunteer, project Bite Mark.
现状
Status.
被认为在去加利福尼亚的
Believed to be en route
威尔森山疾病控制中心的路上
to Mt. Wilson CDC lab, California.
查尔斯·加内特中士  隶属国民警卫队
Sergeant Charles Garnett, National Guard.
被认为与零号病患一起
Believed to be in possession of Patient Zero.
当前位置  费城南部某处
Current location, somewhere south of Philadelphia,
与一群未知平民在一起
accompanied by an unknown number of civilians.
请回复  市民Z
Come in, Citizen Z.
求救  求救
Mayday. Mayday.
我是三角洲X光小队的艾迪生·卡弗
This is Addison Carver with Delta-Xray-Delta.
尝试联系市民Z
Trying to contact Citizen Z.
-请回复  市民Z  -艾迪生·卡弗
- Come in, Citizen Z. - Addy Carver.
-求救  -听上去不像军方的人
- Mayday. - Doesn't sound military.
有点东海岸口音
Slightly east coast accent.
真好奇
I wonder.
只允许安全等级高于九的用户
Level nine top secret clearance only.
那不就是在说我吗
That would be me.
脸书  朋友网  推特  火绒
Facebook, Friendster, Twitter, Tinder.
游览一遍记忆的长廊
A regular trip down memory lane.
总有一天这些都会变成我们遗留下的资料
Someday this will be all that's left of us.
艾迪生·卡弗  又称艾迪
Addison Carver, AKA Addy.
二十六岁  学生
Age twenty-six. Student.
被认为因咬痕研究所而陪同零号病患
Believed to be accompanying Patient Zero to Mount Wilson
去往威尔森山
regarding operation Bite Mark.
最后一次联络是在七天之前
Last contact seven days ago.
当前状态
Status,
单身
Single.
我是说  状态未知
I mean, status unknown.
好个尤物
What a tomato.
怎么了
What?
没别的意思  宝贝  但你该洗澡了
No offense babe, but you need a bath.
是吗
Do I?
可不是
Yeah.
矮油  那您上次换内裤
Oh, okay. Yeah, when was the last time
又是什么时候  小牧童
you changed your underwear goat-boy?
内裤是何物啊
What underwear?
你们看见了吗
Y'all see that?
就是那帮人
That's them, all right.
兔崽子
Bastards.
看上去这回他们想对那倒霉的一家人下手
Looks like they're trying to rob some poor family this time.
有我在就别想  我们走
Not if I have anything to say about it. Come on.
我要是说别去  你们会听吗
Would it matter at all if I said don't do this?
把武器放在地上
Drop your weapons on the ground
不然第一枪就崩了你的脑子
or the first shot takes your head off.
你听见了  放下武器
You heard the man. Drop your weapons.
马上
Now.
这是作甚
What's this?
抢劫
A robbery.
放下武器
Drop your weapons.
快点
Now.
我不想把你们也杀了
I don't want to have to kill you.
千万别下船[语出《现代启示录》]
Never get out of the boat.
大哥  这车还能再快点吗
Yo, can't this thing go any faster?
照这速度  没等到加州我先老死了
I'm gonna die of old age before we get to California.
你想快就下去推车啊
You can always get out and push.
想美事呢姐姐  我这么金贵
No, not me, sister. I'm special.
跟你说话说得我
Talking to you makes me wonder
都不想拯救全人类了
about this whole saving humanity thing.
停车
Stop the car!
天哪  是刚才那一家
Oh, it's the family.
这条路真是走不下去了
We got to get off this road.
下面播送今日最新消息
To update today's top storys:
本日没有任何新消息
absolutley nothing new is going on
只有满世界的死人
in this decimated world of ours.
到处都是绝望  到处一片荒废
It's the same desperation, the same devastation
哪里都一样
everywhere you look.
到底是谁没完没了地播这些小猫视频
And who the hell keeps posting all these cat videos?
我们早该知道弹钢琴的小猫
We should have known piano playing kittens
就是僵尸大灾变的前兆
was a harbinger of the Apocalypse.
收到信号
安静
Quiet!
查尔斯·加内特中士呼叫北极光
This is Sergeant Charles Garnett calling Northern Light.
查尔斯·加内特呼叫北极光
Charles Garnett calling Northern Light.
请回答  北极光
Come in, Northern Light.
能收到吗  市民Z  你能听到吗  完毕
Can you read me? Citizen Z, are you there? Over.
收到  北极光收到加内特呼叫
Yes, this is Northern Light for Garnett.
应答人是市民Z  加内特请讲
Citizen Z hitting you back. Go for Garnett.
太好了  这玩意我们调了好几个小时
Thank God. We've been trying to make this work for hours.
你们拿什么发射的信号
What are you broadcasting on?
薯条小丑男
Uh, Clowny the french fry guy.
我们小队的卡弗拿汽车餐厅的摄像头凑合了下
One of our team, Carver jerry-rigged a drive-thru camera
艾迪·卡弗吗
Addy Carver?
是啊
Yeah.
她在吗  我想打个招呼
Is she there? I wanna say hi.
啊  行
Oh, okay.
你好啊  艾迪
Hi, Addy.
你也好
Hey.
你们那边怎么样
How's it going down there?
说实话不怎么样
Ummm, it's pretty eff'd up actually.
你那边怎么样
How's it going wherever you are?
你也知道了啦  凑合过呗
Aww you know, same ol' same ol'.
光忙着守护世界了
Busy keeping an eye on the world.
我能为你们做什么
What can I do for you folks?
麻烦来万人份的巧克力奶昔和炸薯条
Can we get a chocolate shake and fries for ten thousand men?
拜托能赶在僵尸追上我们之前把正事办了吗
Could we please get on with this before the Zs find us?
慢着  那是摩菲吗
Wait. Is that Murphy?
太好了
Outstanding.
很高兴你还活着  先生
Glad to see you're still alive, sir.
我们要是还沿着大道走的话  就活不多久了
Yeah but he won't be for long if we don't get off this highway.
我们急需空中交通工具
We're in desperate need of alternate transpo.
我们在找飞机  直升机  热气球都行
We're looking for an airplane or a chopper or a hot air balloon.
能飞的就行
Anything airborne.
我倒有个线索
There is one thing.
我一直在监控
I've been monitoring some random transmissions
感染控制紧急指挥部那里
from what's left of the
留下的一些随机信号传输
Emergency Headquarters for Infection Control.
我听得到他们  可我回复他们时得不到应答
I can hear them, but they don't respond when I reply.
而且信号相当混乱
And it's pretty garbled.
麦坎德斯将军可能还藏在那里
General McCandles might still be holed up there.
你们很幸运
You're in luck.
我看到了一架直升机
I have a visual confirmation on that chopper.
看来它还在原来的位置
It looks like it's still there.
在哪里
Where is it?
弗吉尼亚州麦克莱恩市
McLean, Virginia.
在华盛顿特区往西12公里
Twenty clicks due west of Washington DC.
你们去找一个已结构性损坏的高楼
Look for a high-rise with structural damage
楼顶上有一台直升机
and a chopper on the roof.
这样一来  我们还得往南走160公里
Now that's a hundred miles south from here.
我们现在要往西走  不是往南走
We're going west, not south.
-是西  -那你还要不要出发了
- West. - Do you want to get off the road or not?
小伙伴过来了
Puppies and kittens!
我们得走了
We gotta go.
再见  艾迪生
Bye, Addison.
到了再联系我
Call me when you get there.
弗州麦克莱恩市感染控制紧急指挥部
禁区  闲人勿进
跟我期待的很不一样
Not exactly what I was hoping for.
总有一天你会学会不再期待任何事物
One of these days you're gonna learn to quit hoping for things.
你最好别那样想
You better hope not
不然到时我们就会把你丢在路边了
cuz that's when we leave your ass at the side of the road.
站住  报上名来
Halt! Who goes there!
国民警卫队  查尔斯·加内特中士
Sergeant Charles Garnett, National Guard.
这是罗伯塔·沃伦中尉
This is Lieutenant Roberta Warren,
-为何事而来  -也是国民警卫队的
- State your business. - Also National Guard.
我们在执行高优先级任务
We're on a high priority mission
把这位先生送去加州的疾病控制中心研究所
to get this man to a CDC lab in California.
国安局的一名情报人员让我们来这里
We were sent here by an Intell Officer from the NSA
见麦坎德斯将军
to see General McCandles.
我们需要他帮忙找交通工具
We need his help finding transpo.
我们被告知他有一台直升机
We were told he has a helicopter.
没错  他有一台直升机
Yeah, he's got a chopper.
但麦坎德斯将军现在非常忙碌
But General McCandles is a very busy man.
他现在负责指挥整个东海岸
He's got the entire east coast under his command.
他无法去帮那些正在执行自杀任务的
He can't worry about some raggedy ass group of civilians
民间破烂蠢队
on a suicide mission.
我建议在其他感染者找上你们之前赶紧离开吧
I suggest you move on before the infected find you.
我们不是什么民间破烂蠢队  长官
Nothing raggedy ass about this group of civilians, sir.
而且这位先生可以为研制
And this man has important information
僵尸病毒疫苗提供重要信息
about a vaccine for the zombie virus.
他身上有该死的僵尸味道
He smells like a damn Z.
你身上的味道也好不到哪去  化粪池
You don't smell so good yourself, septic tank.
你到底帮不帮我们
You gonna help us or not?
你们想见将军吗
You want to see the General?
那就拿出点诚意
You're going to have to pay a tribute.
拿出诚意向他表达你们的决心
Gesture of goodwill to show him you're serious.
你想要我们拿出怎样的诚意
What kind of tribute you have in mind?
我们的医疗兵已经失踪一年多了
Our medic has been MIA over a year.
我们需要止痛药  抗生素
We need painkillers. Antibiotics.
任何你们有的药物
Anything you got.
我去拿我的医疗包
I'll get my bag.
我有阿司匹林  四环素  西普罗
I got aspirin, tetracycline, cipro.
应该能对付大部分的感染
That should knock out most any infection.
还有奥施康定
And oxycontin.
奥施康定就好  我们需要止痛药
The oxy. We need painkillers.
你到底想不想见将军
You want to see the General or not?
我们只剩这些药物了
This is the last of our supply.
这就对了
That'll do.
现在你们可以见将军了
The General will see you now.
为了什么事来打扰我
Why are you wasting my time?
麦坎德斯将军  长官
General McCandles, sir.
国家警卫队和几个平民
We have a National Guard unit and several civilians
请求跟您说话
requesting permission to speak to you.
亲爱的上帝跟他们一起来的吗
Is sweet Jesus with them?
没有  长官
No, sir.
-那叫他们见鬼去吧  -我想没有
- Then tell them to go to hell! - I don't believe so.
我还有战要打  我要的近距空中支援呢
I've got a war to fight! Where's that close air support I ordered?
告诉海军上将早上8点前潜艇必须到位
Tell the Admiral I need those subs in position by 0800.
B连队  不惜一切代价坚守岗位
Bravo Company, hold your position at all costs.
重复  不惜一切代价
Repeat, all costs.
听到将军说的话了吧
You heard the General.
麦坎德斯将军  长官
General McCandles, sir.
我们在执行一项直接由总统授权的
We're on a mission of extreme importance
非常重要的任务
by direct order from the president.
我们必须要找到能飞到
It's imperative that we find air transport
-加利福尼亚的  -抱歉  我很忙
-to Mt. Wilson CDC lab - Sorry, I'm busy.
威尔森山疾病控制中心研究所的飞机
in California.
我的增援部队什么时候到
Where are my reinforcements?
你听到了  该走了
You heard the man. Time to go.
这样就完事了吗
That's it?
我要揍到你把奥斯康定吐出来
I've a good mind to make you barf up my oxycontin.
多克[医生]  多克[医生]  冷静点
Doc! Doc! Stand down!
你刚才说的"医生"  真的是名医生吗
Did you say Doc? As in doctor?
是的  我们的队伍里有一名医生
Yeah, our team includes a medical doctor.
你刚才为什么没说  让他进来
Why didn't you say so? Send him up.
我有个手下受伤了  需要被治疗
I have a wounded man in need of medical attention.
只准医生进去  其他人在外面等着
Just the doctor. The rest of you wait here.
我自己就行
I got this.
好吧
All right.
跟他说说借用直升机的事
Hey, hey, hey. Talk to him about the chopper.
那个贱种
Son of a bitch.
我还想留着奥斯康定
I was saving that oxy
到加利福尼亚开派对的时候用呢
for a party when we got to Cali.
你就是那个医生吗
You the medic?
的确是我
I am indeed.
你是将军吗
You the General?
亚瑟·C·麦坎德斯将军
General Arthur C. McCandles.
指挥官  中央司令部
Commander, Central Command,
感染反应部队
Infection Response Forces.
你受伤的手下在哪
Where's your wounded man?
就是我
Right here.
这不是被僵尸咬伤的
It's not a bite.
看起来不太好
This looks bad.
真的很糟
Real bad.
只是被抓了一下
It's just a scratch.
不  这  这更像一个坏疽
No, that's... that's more like gangrene.
你能保住我这条腿吗
Can you save the leg?
恐怕不能  将军
I'm afraid not, General.
它已经向外蔓延了
It's already starting to spread.
不久僵尸病毒就会蔓延全身
Soon the Z virus will take over.
我只能在你变成僵尸的时候
All I can do at this point is show you mercy
对你"施以仁慈"了
when the time comes.
这就是你的诊断吗
You call that a diagnosis?
我只能实话实说
I call it the truth.
你不久就会死去
You're gonna die.
很快
And soon.
上一个家伙也是这么说的
That's what the last guy said.
快看这是谁
Look who.
你觉得怎么样  小狗
What do you think, pup?
能不能变成我们的下一个小伙伴呢
Could we use another friend?
我也是这么想的
My thoughts exactly.
速度真快
That was quick.
你在北极怎么样了
How are things at the North Pole?
好极了  今天看到美丽的极光了
Awesome. Beautiful Aurora today.
你那边怎么样
How's your day going?
有点寂寞  能有个聊天的人真好
Kinda lonely. Nice to have somebody to talk to.
我知道那种感觉  我在这也很寂寞
I know the feeling. Gets lonely here too.
尽管一直忙着关注整个地球
Keeping an eye on the planet keeps you busy though.
我知道你在看着我们就感到很安心
I feel safer just knowing you're there.
感觉你很酷[冷静]
You seem so cool.
希望我能见到你
I wish I could meet you in person.
虽然非常忙  但是我保证我们能见面
Super busy, but I'm sure that could be arranged.
你现在在做什么
What are you doing right now?
你懂的
Aww you know.
跟以前一样呗
Same ol', same ol'.
一千零九十
One thousand ninety.
一千零九十一
One thousand ninety-one.
一千零九十二
One thousand and ninety-two.
多克怎么样了
Okay, what's going on with Doc?
伙计们  如果我们不尽快离开这里
Guys, if we don't get out of here soon
事情可能就糟糕了
this could get ugly.
你应该说变得更糟
Oh, you mean uglier.
你们听到了吗
Do you hear that?
听到什么
Hear what?
我什么也没听到
I don't hear anything.
听起来好像是多克
Sounds like Doc.
快住口
Make it stop!
是多克没错  但是他到底在哪
That's Doc all right. But where the hell is he?
在上面的某处
Somewhere up there.
我们上去找他
We're going up after him.
不  你们不能进去
No, you don't.
让我们上去
Let us up now.
没有将军的命令谁也不能上去
Nobody goes upstairs without the General's orders.
现在就让我们上去
We go up now
不然让你的大脑变豆脑
or I scramble your egg-brain inside the shell.
你会后悔的
You'll be sorry.
你也会后悔的  因为你和我们一起
So will you cuz you're coming up with us.
一万  侧面掩护
10K! Cover our flank.
别让人或僵尸跟上来
Don't let man or zombie follow us up.
遵命
Yes, sir.
1093个
One thousand ninety-three.
一箭双雕
No.
应该是第1094个
Ninety-four.
将军在几楼
What floor is the General on?
在顶楼
Top floor.
拜托  他可是将军
He's the General, man.
他还能在哪一层呢
What floor do you think he's on?
这一切都是幻觉
My world is but an illusion.
天呐  为什么我以前没有多注意
Oh God, why didn't I pay better attention
和我约会的那个信佛的妞
to that sweet little Buddhist chick I dated?
保持冷静
Stay calm.
我确定他们...
I'm sure they're...
我确定他们在守着你
I'm sure they're watching you right now.
他们正在找你
They're looking for you.
他们现在正在找你
They're looking for you right now.
他们不可能抛弃你
There's no way they'd just leave you here
不会让你卡在通风井里
trapped in the air shaft with an ugly-ass zombie
和一个等着吃人的丑僵尸在一起
waiting to eat my face off!
等等
Oh, wait.
这还差不多
Oh, that's more like it.
我这是为特殊情况省下来的
I was saving this for a special occasion.
就像现在
Like now.
加油  坚持住
Come on, suck it up.
加油  挺住
Come on. Come on.
这他妈是个好东西
That's good shit, man.
冷静点
Chill!
救命呀
Help!
现在做什么
Now what?
准备好见招拆招
Be ready for anything.
我有提过吗
Did I mention that
除了僵尸
the one thing I have a phobia of aside
我最怕的就是电梯
from zombies is elevators.
你们真不应该去惹将军
Shouldn't have messed with the General.
这里是不是越来越热了
Is it getting hot in here?
快点  把该死的门打开
Hey, come on. Open the damn door.
我要出去
I got to get out of here.
摩菲  放松
Relax, Murphy.
不  我要出去  这里氧气不足
No, no, I got to get out. There's not enough oxygen.
冷静点
Chill out!
马克
Mack!
宝贝  我在这
I'm here, babe.
为什么停了
Hey, why aren't we moving?
马上就会启动
It'll start in a second.
儿子  谢谢你
Thank you, son.
真不错
It's good.
我现在能为你做些什么
Can I do anything for you?
确保这些结都系紧了
Make sure those knots are tight.
要不了多久了
It's not gonna be long now.
是双活结  按照你教我那样打的
It's double-half-hitch. Just like you taught me.
再确认一下吧
Just be sure.
答应我
Promise me
时间一到
you'll do what we talked about
你要按照我们说好的做
when the time comes.
答应我
Promise me.
我保证
I promise.
按照我们说好的来
Just like we talked about.
我发誓
I swear.
别发誓
Don't swear.
你母亲不喜欢发誓
Your mother never liked that.
我保证
I promise.
好
Good.
我一直相信你能做正确的事
I could always trust you to do the right thing.
你是个好孩子
You're a good boy.
你母亲
Your mother,
她会为日后的你而自豪
she'd be proud of the man you're growing up to be.
再给我抽一口
Give me another puff.
行吗
Will ya?
你现在别乱来好吗
Ya know, now don't take offense.
比你那张脸更恐怖的
But the only thing worse than that mug of yours
就是你的口臭了
is your breath.
别咬我手指  畜生
Not my fingers, you animal!
我是在请你抽最后一口好东西
I was offering you the last hit.
得了  都便宜了我自己吧
Well, fine. I'll bogart it myself then.
我跟你说这玩意儿可是用途广泛
A thousand and one uses, I tell ya.
该死的
Well I'll be damned.
我看你是被熏醉了
I think you're stoned.
矮油  疫苗之类都可以省了
Hell, we don't need a vaccine.
只需要几百万吨的优质大麻
Just need a few billion tons of some primo Ganja,
就能天下太平了
and the world would be just fine.
摩根·亨利医生
Doctor Morgan Henley.
你那个吸饱大麻烟气的脑袋
Does that name ring a bell
觉得这个名字听起来耳熟吗
in any of those cannabinol soaked brain cells you have left?
我一定也是醉了
I must be really stoned.
产科医生是吗
Obstetrics, huh?
真想知道那是怎样的感觉
I wonder what that must have been like.
把那些美丽的小天使带到尘世间来
Bringing all them beautiful little angels into the world.
我是说那么多奇迹发生时你都能在场见证
I mean just to be present for so many miracles.
结果那些婴儿都长大变成了僵尸也真令人痛心
Yeah, it's a bummer all those babies grew up to be zombies.
你知道吗
You know,
我在外头有个孩子
I got a kid out there somewhere.
我从没告诉过其它人
I never told anybody that before.
我十九岁就有的他
I had him when I was 19.
当时我太年轻了
Too young.
应该陪他长大的时候我都不怎么在他身边
Wasn't really around for him like I should've been.
从没能真正了解他
Never really got to know him.
我一直在告诉自己
Kept telling myself maybe you know
或许某一天我会和他通个电话
someday I...I would just call him up.
来弥补我没能陪伴他的时光
Make up for lost time.
逝去的时光  逝去的时光
Lost time. Lost time.
我甚至都不知道他是死是活
And I don't even know if he's alive or dead.
救命呀
Help!
来人啊
Somebody!
有人吗
Anybody!
救命
Help!
在增援部队抵达之前
Bravo Company must hold their positions
B连队必须要挺住
until the reinforcements arrive.
一旦他们的前线崩溃
If their line is broken,
就再也无法阻止受感染者
there's nothing to stop the infected
从本地向海洋移动了
between here and the ocean.
你告诉那个中校
You tell that wing commander
要是他不能马上安排飞机起飞
if he doesn't get those planes in the air right now
我就要亲自去他那里
I'm gonna come down there personally
把他的脑袋从肩膀上卸下来
and tear his head off his shoulders
用他鲜血淋漓的头骨把那群僵尸给揍趴下
and beat the damn zombie horde to death with his bloody skull.
看看这些送上门来的家伙们
What do we have here?
屡教不改的人真是不听话啊
Insubordinate curs can't take no for an answer?
我们走着瞧吧
We'll see about that, eh?
电梯怎么不动了  发生什么事了
Why aren't we moving? What's going on?
行了  你们都冷静下
All right, everyone needs to relax.
别想糊弄我们
Don't mess with us.
我没在糊弄你  伙计
I'm not messing with you, man.
一旦出事  第一个受死的就是你
Anything happens, you'll be the first to go.
我没法再待在这里了
I got to get out of here!
摩菲  别出去
Murphy! No!
不要开枪
Don't fire!
早知道我抽那个家伙时下手就该再狠点
I should have slapped that fool harder.
摩菲
Murphy!
摩菲  摩菲
Murphy! Murphy!
行了沃伦  你跟我来
All right Warren, you come with me.
你们在这里等他
You guys stay here in case he comes back.
了解
Got it.
你们还好吗
You okay?
我们出去吧
Let's get out of here.
伙计
Dude,
你真的开始让我觉得反胃了
you're really starting to marsh my mellow.
我一小时前就该用你了
Well I coulda used you about an hour ago.
听着伙计
Look, man.
跟你在一起挺愉快
It's been fun,
不过我觉得该让你归西了
but I think it's time you go home now.
你开始吓着我了  伙计
You're starting to creep me out, man.
我们做个了断吧
Let's just get this over with.
摩根·亨利医生
Doctor Morgan Henley.
我仁慈地结束你的生命
I give you mercy.
好了
Okay.
行了
There.
现在我该怎么出去呢
Now how am I gonna get out of here?
沃伦
Warren!
救命  有人吗
Help! Somebody!
多克  多克
Doc? Doc?
有人吗
Anybody!
多克  是你吗
Doc, is that you?
摩菲
Murphy?
摩菲  是你吗
Murphy, is that you?
撑住  多克
Hang in there, Doc.
会有人来救你的
Someone will come help you.
不过不是我
Just not me.
禁区
我的弹药用光了
I'm out of ammo.
我也是
Me too.
瞧瞧这是谁啊
Well look who.
我想他们是最后几个了
I think that's the last of them.
大家都没事吧
Is everybody okay?
有人看到摩菲了吗
Anybody seen Murphy?
摩菲  摩菲
Murphy! Murphy!
别喊了  我在这
You don't have to shout. I'm right here.
你接近人的时候别鬼鬼祟祟地行吗
You don't sneak up on people
现在是僵尸时代
in the zombie apocalypse, okay?
对不起  我错了
Sorry, sorry.
我知道多克在哪儿
I know where Doc is.
哪里
Where?
我的天哪
Holy shit.
我没子弹了
I'm out of ammo.
我也是
Me too.
我有这个
I got this.
加内特
Garnett!
趴下
Take cover!
不
No!
大家没事吧
Is everybody okay?
没事
Yeah.
摩菲  多克在哪里
Murphy, where's Doc?
他就在通风井里面
He was down that air shaft.
什么
What?
我们去找直升机吧
Let's go find that helicopter
然后离开这里
and get out of here.
走吧
Now.
总统女士  无意冒犯
No disrespect Madame President,
不过你都没法好好带着一群幼儿园的孩子
but you're not fit to lead a gang of kindergartners
打泥巴仗
in a dirt clod war.
更别想在这国难深重之时统领国家
Let alone this great nation in a moment of grave national peril
就像现在我们都处于水深火热之中
like we find ourselves in now.
我一直等着你们呢
I've been waiting for you.
啊  垃圾
Ah, crap.
没有一件有用的
Nothing works anymore.
都没用
Nothing.
你们究竟想要什么
What do you people want anyway?
我们正在执行一项有可能拯救人类的任务
We're on a mission that just might save the human race.
这个人的血液中有抗体
This man has antibodies in his blood
能用来制造僵尸疫苗
needed to make a zombie vaccine.
我们负责把他护送到
We've been tasked with getting him
加利福尼亚的疾病控制中心研究所
to a CDC lab in California.
要活的
Alive.
我们需要你的直升机
We need your helicopter.
见鬼  你们怎么不早说
Well hell, why didn't you say so sooner?
我亲自开直升机带你们去
I'll fly you there myself.
她很漂亮  对吧
She's beautiful, isn't she?
怎么回事  你在开玩笑吗
What is this, some kind of joke?
她的确需要好好维修一下了
Sure, she needs a little maintenance.
不过
But,
只要细心呵护她
with some TLC,
再帮忙给她找来一些零件
a little help scrounging a few spare parts,
我很快就会把你们送到加利福尼亚的
I'll have you to California in no time.
混蛋
Jackass!
我的朋友就为了这一堆垃圾送了命
A friend of mine died trying to get to that pile of junk.
你跟多克是朋友
You and Doc were friends?
我们一起玩过牌...  一次
We played cards...once.
这是战争  小子
This is war, son.
我们都失去过朋友
We've all lost friends.
妈的  我认识的所有人都死了
Hell, everybody I ever knew is dead.
我怎么就不吃惊呢
Why am I not surprised?
知道吗  我可不喜欢你
You know I don't like you.
那请先排个队
Well get in line.
麦坎德斯将军
General McCandles.
长官
Sir.
谢谢  但我想我们还是另想办法运送吧
Thank you, but I think we'll find alternate transportation.
你们觉得我疯了  是不是
You think I'm insane, don't you?
也许我的确是疯了
Well maybe I am.
死了那么多人
Too much death.
很多人英年早逝
Too many good men sent to an early grave.
那么多僵尸
Too many zombies.
后退  我来对付
Stand down! I got this!
来啊  你们这些蔑视上帝的吃脑蠢货
Come here you Godless brain eating scum!
咱们地狱见啦
I'll see you in Hell!
多克呢
What happened to Doc?
他没挺过来
He didn't make it.
有僵尸
Zombies.
天啊  那是...
Oh God, is that...
是多克
It's Doc.
谁来...
Someone's gotta...
我来吧
I'll do it.
斯蒂文·多克·贝克
Steven "Doc" Beck.
我仁慈地结束你的生命
I give you mercy.
搞什么鬼  沃伦
What the hell, Warren?
你这是要杀我吗
You trying to kill me?
你还活着吗
You're alive?
废他妈话  我活好好的
Damn straight I'm alive.
我们以为你死了
We thought you were dead.
哥也这么以为呢
Well so did I.
不知哪个傻瓜往我被困的通风道
Some numbskull threw a grenade
扔了颗手雷
in the air shaft I was stuck in.
赶紧过来吧
Well hurry up!
给
Here.
服了你了
Come on.
亲一个  宝贝
Give me a kiss, baby.
好吧  我也不想再烦你了
Well I should let you go.
我知道你肯定忙着
I'm sure you're busy with
警惕着世界和身边的一切
keeping an eye on the world and all.
是啊
Yeah.
我养了只小饿狗  我得赶紧喂它了
I got a hungry dog here I better go feed.
跟你聊得很愉快
Nice talking to you.
希望某天我们能见面
I hope we get to meet someday.
我真的很想见你
I'd really like that.
晚安
Good night.
甜美的小公主
Sweet prince.
市民Z广播  聊天
晚安  美丽的女士
Good night, fair lady.
下面这首歌献给所有孤独的人们
Here's a song for all the lonely people out there,
这首歌写得是关于那些还活着的人
which is just about everybody that's left.
所以如果在大灾变中  有朋友陪伴着你
So if you've got somebody to go through the Apocalypse with,
你一定要好好掩护他
you better watch their backs.
因为所剩的人已经不多了
Cuz there ain't many of us left.
是的
And oh yeah,
艾迪·卡弗
同时我也想把这首歌送给艾迪生·卡弗
I'd like to dedicate this song to Addison Carver,
无论你身在何处
wherever you are.
同时我也想把这首歌送给艾迪生·卡弗
I'd like to dedicate this song to Addison Carver,
无论你身在何处
wherever you are.
我只跟他通过两次话  拜托
I talked to the guy twice. Come on.
知道吗  孩子
You know kid,
我一直在想  你跟我说的你爸爸的事
I've been thinking about what you told me about your dad
还有  你希望他知道你做了正确的事
and how you wished he knew you did the right thing
信守承诺  仁慈地结束他的生命
giving him mercy like you promised.
所以呢
Yeah?
我只想让你明白
Well I just want you to know
你爸爸知道你为他做了什么
your dad knows what you did for him.
他也知道你做得对
And he knows you did the right thing.
你信守了承诺
You kept your promise.
谢谢
Thanks.
对不起  爸爸
I'm sorry, papa.
我爱你
I love you.